<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Vernikovskaya E.A.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating presentations.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_6/%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%82%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA_hue19078ae8b2f9e4fb5fcd0257ce87952_113933_405a5d01f1882eb2f35d29b2a0be45dc.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_6/%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%82%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA_hue19078ae8b2f9e4fb5fcd0257ce87952_113933_cac1a29210bfc6b1b7239549994c0e85.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_6/%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%82%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA_hue19078ae8b2f9e4fb5fcd0257ce87952_113933_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_6/%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%82%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA_hue19078ae8b2f9e4fb5fcd0257ce87952_113933_405a5d01f1882eb2f35d29b2a0be45dc.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A high-quality presentation can create the most favorable impressions about you and become your assistant during the performance. At the same time, hastily prepared slides with many errors in design and content will demonstrate your negligence and become a reason for numerous quibbles. Do not rush to make slides right away, but rather start working with careful preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparatory-work&#34;&gt;Preparatory work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, make a detailed presentation plan. In the plan, describe the structure of the report, and in front of each element of this structure, specify the approximate number of slides based on their total number. If the optimal number of slides was not announced to you at the upcoming event, then use common sense: 20-30 slides is too much for a small report, 3-5 slides are too few. Keep in mind that the slides should reflect really meaningful information, and not contain separate pieces of text that will sound in your report without it. First of all, it should be statistical information, various graphs, diagrams, drawings — everything that will make your report more visual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-approximate-plan-may-be-as-follows&#34;&gt;AN APPROXIMATE PLAN MAY BE AS FOLLOWS:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentation of the report&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide No. 1. Information about the work, the author…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide No. 2. Definition of relevance and problems. Table about…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide No. 3. Definition of other elements of the introduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main part&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide No.4. Theoretical provisions…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide No. 5. Diagram about…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide No. 6. Drawing…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide No. 9. Conclusions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide No. 10. Contact details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before creating a presentation, carefully study the requirements for this type of work (see below). If specific requirements have been announced at the event for which the presentation is being prepared, do not ignore them. Ask for sample presentations. If you are preparing a presentation for graduation, be sure to discuss the presentation plan with your supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-requirements&#34;&gt;Presentation Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The presentation should reflect the content of the report and not have elements that the speaker does not plan to comment on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each slide should be clear and understandable to the audience for which the report is intended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slides should not be overloaded with information, as well as be meaningless. It is advisable to use short sentences and, if possible, exclude words that complicate reading or do not carry a load (introductory words, complex terms, long speech phrases, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The colors of individual elements of the slide and all slides as a whole should be combined with each other. If necessary, use the color matching tables. Contrasting tones should be used for the background and text, but the background should not be too bright so as not to tire the audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide design and auxiliary information such as control buttons should not distract viewers from the content of the presentation. The same goes for animation effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_6/%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%8B_hub83e7dfe6cf35d51352fd1ca516cfd5a_1143178_bc5220ce951493e786aa2991f6d6bf9d.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_6/%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%8B_hub83e7dfe6cf35d51352fd1ca516cfd5a_1143178_2635220adf82403eafa7add36ccb5009.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_6/%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%8B_hub83e7dfe6cf35d51352fd1ca516cfd5a_1143178_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_6/%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%8B_hub83e7dfe6cf35d51352fd1ca516cfd5a_1143178_bc5220ce951493e786aa2991f6d6bf9d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;412&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mistakes-when-creating-a-presentation-and-speaking&#34;&gt;Mistakes when creating a presentation and speaking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are too many slides. With this approach, the audience gets tired of listening to the report and realizes that you have not worked with highlighting the main thing. If you have presented less than a dozen slides, you can also create a negative impression of your hard work and serious attitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The slides are easy to read on the monitor, but not visible in a large audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The slides are too mismatched: the text is located at different levels in different slides, decorated with different fonts, the elements are arranged randomly, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The presentation causes a negative reaction from a grin to outrage due to overloaded animation effects or too flashy design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are violations in the content component: the presentation poorly reveals the material of the report, the conclusions are not confirmed by reliable sources, spelling and other errors are present, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The slide show does not coincide with the speaker&amp;rsquo;s speech.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The speaker failed to interest the audience either with the report or with the slides presented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The speaker gets confused in his own presentation, flipping through the slides in different directions, or violates the logic of the narrative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-presentation-and-refining-it&#34;&gt;Creating a presentation and refining it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most suitable program for creating a presentation with rich functionality is Microsoft PowerPoint. You can easily present tables, graphs, photos or video clips in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the surface, working with it seems simple, since creating slides or inserting text, drawings and other elements into them is not particularly difficult. However, the process becomes much more complicated when it comes to correcting an element. Here it turns out that it is not so easy to change the theme of a separate slide, bring all the elements to a single style or adjust the effects as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to make a high-quality presentation, and not work at the &amp;ldquo;blunder&amp;rdquo; level, start creating it long before the event or use outside help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the presentation is completed, be sure to test it several times in different conditions. The first test is a demonstration on your own computer. Make sure that you have not made the above mistakes, and also evaluate your work as a whole. A properly designed presentation should evoke a sense of harmony, style and the feeling that its author has taste. After that, show the presentation to the teacher if you are preparing to defend your graduation thesis. If you speak at a conference or other event on your own initiative, consult with experienced teachers to make your presentation more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second check is carried out directly in the auditorium where the planned event will take place. Students often get lost just because they don&amp;rsquo;t know how to flip through slides using the remote control. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, it&amp;rsquo;s no more difficult than switching channels on the TV remote. Preparations for a major event usually begin a few hours before it starts, so you will have time to learn how to use the appropriate equipment or correct unsuccessful slides.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (15.04.24 - 21.04.24)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;рабочая-неделя&#34;&gt;Рабочая неделя&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-week&#34;&gt;Work week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week has been boring!!! Nothing interesting happened:(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went dancing on Wednesday. We danced &amp;ldquo;deja vu&amp;rdquo; - txt. At first I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like this choreography, but then I really liked it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, at the matanalysis, we started going through double integrals and I was very happy, because of all mathematics, I love integrals! I can&amp;rsquo;t even find the words how much I love integrals!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emoji: 🥱💃∫&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Double integral&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_5/%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B3%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BB_hu1cb6f4a525b95779f65a7b199e199725_47241_f24fb4b32403fc9aa9dfe3ab33694964.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_5/%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B3%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BB_hu1cb6f4a525b95779f65a7b199e199725_47241_9679d07dead37c7105d92989d74fc137.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_5/%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B3%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BB_hu1cb6f4a525b95779f65a7b199e199725_47241_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_5/%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B3%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BB_hu1cb6f4a525b95779f65a7b199e199725_47241_f24fb4b32403fc9aa9dfe3ab33694964.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekend&#34;&gt;Weekend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Saturday and I&amp;rsquo;m doing stage 4 of an individual project.
On Sunday it&amp;rsquo;s my turn to clean, so tomorrow I will clean the hut(((&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emoji:  💻🧹&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plans-for-next-week&#34;&gt;Plans for next week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take an Arduino kit and do a computer workshop lab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have more rest :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emoji: 🤖💻😴&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ps&#34;&gt;P.S.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a very strong wind and rain on Friday. I don&amp;rsquo;t like this weather(
The sun would be better!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (25.03.24 - 31.03.24)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-week&#34;&gt;Work week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week has been more or less easy. On Monday, I missed a remote couple in discrete mathematics, as I was on my way to beat a tattoo. This is my very first tattoo and I am very happy. It depicts a palm tree, a beach umbrella, a chaise longue, a wave and the sun. And the meaning of this tattoo is like this: I always wanted to live by the sea or ocean, lie on the beach, so that there was a palm tree on my right and a beach umbrella on my left and it was +40 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, I wrote a test paper on mathematical analysis. I have solved all the tasks and I really hope that everything is right for me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emoji: 🏖️🌊☀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;My tattoo&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_3/tattoo_huaefa815810cf480d5bb2d4b66beb7f9b_74784_e39c33172063f6d53c5550225c80d8bc.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_3/tattoo_huaefa815810cf480d5bb2d4b66beb7f9b_74784_03bc614faf54da208b66ce4eb9ae8218.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_3/tattoo_huaefa815810cf480d5bb2d4b66beb7f9b_74784_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_3/tattoo_huaefa815810cf480d5bb2d4b66beb7f9b_74784_e39c33172063f6d53c5550225c80d8bc.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;628&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekend&#34;&gt;Weekend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a rest all day on Saturday! And on Sunday, I went to the grocery store to buy food, because I only had a pack of ketchup and a pack of eggs in the refrigerator. When I returned home, I cooked shrimp in cream sauce for the first time and realized that I finally learned how to cook!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening, I met with a friend and we were preparing for a CD in discrete mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emoji: 🍤🛒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plans-for-next-week&#34;&gt;Plans for next week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat the choreography of the dance &amp;ldquo;LALALALA&amp;rdquo; - Stray kids by Wednesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare for the CD in discrete mathematics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll make it in time)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emoji: 🕺📚⏰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ps&#34;&gt;P.S.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was +17 degrees in Moscow at the weekend!!! I really like warm weather.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markup languages. LaTeX.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-latex&#34;&gt;What is LaTeX?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LaTEX (pronounced &amp;ldquo;latech&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;latech&amp;rdquo;) is a tool for creating professional documents. It is based on the WYSIWYM editing paradigm (what I see is what I mean), that is, the user is required to focus only on the contents of the document, leaving its formatting to the program. Instead of manually distributing the text on the page, as is done in Microsoft Word or LibreOffice Writer, you can simply type it, allowing LaTeX to do the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-i-need-latex&#34;&gt;Why do I need LaTeX?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool is used everywhere to create scientific documents, write books, as well as many other forms of publications. It not only allows you to create beautifully designed documents, but also gives users the opportunity to quickly implement such complex elements of a printed set as mathematical expressions, tables, links and bibliographies, obtaining consistent markup across all sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the availability of a large number of open libraries (more on this later), the possibilities of LaTEX become almost limitless. These libraries empower users even more by allowing you to add footnotes, draw diagrams, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most compelling reasons why many people use LaTeX is to separate the content of a document from its style. This means that after writing the content, you can easily change its appearance. Similarly, you can create one document style and use it to standardize the appearance of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allows scientific journals to create templates for the materials offered for consideration. Such templates have a set markup, as a result of which only the content remains to be added. In fact, there are hundreds of similar templates, ranging from various summaries to slide presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlights-of-the-work&#34;&gt;Highlights of the work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with LaTeX boils down to writing code that has several basic components and fragments. At the same time, you need to know a few nuances:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-text formulas are surrounded on both sides by $ signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off formulas (placed in a separate line) are surrounded by $ signs or a pair of commands [ and ]. Formulas enclosed in $ are always centered horizontally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-text formulas, except for the shortest ones, are typed in a separate line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following tags are used to align the document: \flushleft — on the left edge, \flushrigth — on the right edge, \center — in the center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verbatim&amp;rsquo;s default environment helps to correctly display even complex program code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most mathematical functions and symbols, as well as brackets, matrices and systems of equations in LaTeX syntax are indicated by tags starting with the \ symbol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To work with expressions that take up more than one line (that is, for careful text wrapping or calculations), you can use the \ separator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The letters of the Greek language and lemniscate, the infinity symbol and others are entered as tags. stored in one place, you risk losing everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-use-latex-in-the-editor-myoffice-text&#34;&gt;How to use LaTeX in the editor &amp;ldquo;MyOffice Text&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In MyOffice, LaTeX is used to enter formulas and mathematical expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To insert a formula, go to the &amp;ldquo;Insert&amp;rdquo; menu on the toolbar, select the &amp;ldquo;Formula&amp;rdquo; item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;MyOffice Text&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_4/1_hu1d25f9e9e2778b12fb33b8e49400fddf_50115_bcc50253a70ad05160832327a7b2d948.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_4/1_hu1d25f9e9e2778b12fb33b8e49400fddf_50115_0fb835475ab1f439c823f463a6b1c715.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_4/1_hu1d25f9e9e2778b12fb33b8e49400fddf_50115_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_4/1_hu1d25f9e9e2778b12fb33b8e49400fddf_50115_bcc50253a70ad05160832327a7b2d948.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;497&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After confirmation, a pop-up window will appear with the &amp;ldquo;LaTeX Expression&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Preview&amp;rdquo; fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Formula Window&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_4/2_huc38827a0111a8862111cabaad793a433_14730_64f8c2006d355999f440da50793898e9.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_4/2_huc38827a0111a8862111cabaad793a433_14730_bed7dc058252655075ce32958371f66f.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_4/2_huc38827a0111a8862111cabaad793a433_14730_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_4/2_huc38827a0111a8862111cabaad793a433_14730_64f8c2006d355999f440da50793898e9.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;480&#34;
               height=&#34;480&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, we introduce a simple formula for a certain integral of the function f(x) on the interval [a, b]. It will look like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\int_a^b f(x) dx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Preview field, you can immediately see what the final formula will look like. This is convenient — if necessary, you can make edits immediately on the spot, and not after inserting the formula into the document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Example formula&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_4/3_hufeceaa9f087493c23a514ca2988c6fa8_15227_9279d864d8c6bc4e1936d531ed9a6694.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_4/3_hufeceaa9f087493c23a514ca2988c6fa8_15227_793689d4b593d1fd0b50ac13f07d03c9.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_4/3_hufeceaa9f087493c23a514ca2988c6fa8_15227_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_4/3_hufeceaa9f087493c23a514ca2988c6fa8_15227_9279d864d8c6bc4e1936d531ed9a6694.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;488&#34;
               height=&#34;488&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After inserting the formula, it, like any other object in the MyOffice Text editor, can be moved, aligned, and even resized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to edit the formula, just double—click on it with the left mouse button - a pop-up window with edit and preview fields will open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can delete a formula using the [Backspace], [Del] keys or a special button on the toolbar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Deleting a formula&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_4/4_hu4ce39a933827e1887341b12e343f9485_38905_f9656c855fd2dd0e1dda19d4c19bfa81.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_4/4_hu4ce39a933827e1887341b12e343f9485_38905_33a2c4cfdc1ba197ba5079f785efd412.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_4/4_hu4ce39a933827e1887341b12e343f9485_38905_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_4/4_hu4ce39a933827e1887341b12e343f9485_38905_f9656c855fd2dd0e1dda19d4c19bfa81.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;403&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can work with more complex formulas in a similar way. For example, consider a conditional function with four variables. For the convenience of reading the formula, we will immediately divide it into lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f(a,b,\delta, \gamma) =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\frac{&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\sum \limits_{n=0}^{\infty} S_n \tan \left( \frac{104-2\delta \pi}{\mu} \right)+\gamma&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\mathcal{F} {g(a,b)}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately in the preview field we can see that the formula is displayed correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;A more complex formula&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_4/5_hue900ade123a07779212010aaf3492a67_25023_24f138d43c4653e08d159fd9870720d7.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_4/5_hue900ade123a07779212010aaf3492a67_25023_84ba0b1a0a14f539debe39e69b7ffa7d.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_4/5_hue900ade123a07779212010aaf3492a67_25023_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_4/5_hue900ade123a07779212010aaf3492a67_25023_24f138d43c4653e08d159fd9870720d7.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;504&#34;
               height=&#34;510&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formatting is preserved when pasted into a document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is noteworthy that the formula editor helps to find errors. For example, if we put an extra space in the \gamma operator in the specified formula, when inserting the editor &amp;ldquo;MyOffice Text&amp;rdquo; will show an error — it will highlight the place in red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Formula with error&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_4/6_hu1d1ae8db25992ebea9f88b5e4f7410f7_10419_397691af03af26cc28c454b66c5afd67.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_4/6_hu1d1ae8db25992ebea9f88b5e4f7410f7_10419_4fad9b0ce96ecb92cd21ebf3b23158e1.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_4/6_hu1d1ae8db25992ebea9f88b5e4f7410f7_10419_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_4/6_hu1d1ae8db25992ebea9f88b5e4f7410f7_10419_397691af03af26cc28c454b66c5afd67.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;546&#34;
               height=&#34;194&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is convenient and protects against accidental errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With LaTex, you can write not only formulas, but also edit texts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (4.03.24 - 10.03.24)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-week&#34;&gt;Working week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was memorable and special! March 8 is International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day, so Friday was a day off. In general, the week passed quickly and unnoticed. I attended the university as usual and went to dance practice on Wednesday evening. On Thursday, I returned home to my hometown of Nizhny Novgorod by train, as there is a long weekend ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emoji: 🌸🚂💃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekend&#34;&gt;Weekend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went go-karting on weekends (3 times already in my life). I have almost overtaken everyone and finally arrived the 3rd, not the last! Then we went to the shooting range. We fired a pistol and a submachine gun. I really liked it, and my mom was surprised why I shoot so well. And on Sunday, the whole family went bowling. We had a great time, played bowling and ate pizza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emoji: 🏎️🔫🎳🍕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plans-for-next-week&#34;&gt;Plans for next week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already returned to Moscow on Tuesday. And I have a lot to do!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5th and 6th laboratory work on computer architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the second stage of an individual computer architecture project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;laboratory work and computer workshop report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll make it in time)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emoji: 🌆📚✨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ps&#34;&gt;P.S.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And on March 9th, my bios Min Yoongi&amp;rsquo;s birthday (he turned 31 this year). Traditionally, I bought a small piece of cake and blew out the candles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Yoongi&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_1/%D1%8E%D0%BD%D0%B3%D0%B8_huc59cca40bf6037487c5ca8c9b23ee9e2_131720_5dc5f921de7727b688d02234b4a7fa2f.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_1/%D1%8E%D0%BD%D0%B3%D0%B8_huc59cca40bf6037487c5ca8c9b23ee9e2_131720_791e10eaa38426bfa0bf8a718c6c01d5.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_1/%D1%8E%D0%BD%D0%B3%D0%B8_huc59cca40bf6037487c5ca8c9b23ee9e2_131720_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_1/%D1%8E%D0%BD%D0%B3%D0%B8_huc59cca40bf6037487c5ca8c9b23ee9e2_131720_5dc5f921de7727b688d02234b4a7fa2f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version control. Git.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-version-control-system&#34;&gt;About the version control system&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a &amp;ldquo;version control system&amp;rdquo; and why is it important? A version control system is a system that records changes to a file or set of files over time and allows you to revert to a specific version later. For file version control, this book will use the source code of the software as an example, although in fact you can use version control for almost any type of file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a graphic or web designer and want to save every version of an image or layout (most likely you will), a version control system (hereinafter referred to as VCS) is just what you need. It allows you to return files to the state they were in before the changes, return the project to its original state, see the changes, see who last changed something and caused the problem, who set the task and when, and much more. Using VCS also means in general that if you break something or lose files, you can safely fix everything. In addition to everything, you will get it all without any extra effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Local version control systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people use copying files to a separate directory as a version control method (perhaps even a time-stamped directory, if they are smart enough). This approach is very common because of its simplicity, but it is incredibly prone to errors. You can easily forget which directory you are in and accidentally change the wrong file or copy the wrong files that you wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to solve this problem, programmers have long ago developed local VCS with a simple database that stores records of all changes in files, thereby monitoring revisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Local version control&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_2/1_hufcb633eabb4ce248b64f5422c2c69f5a_20255_7dea048445c495e32aed14824d931f27.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_2/1_hufcb633eabb4ce248b64f5422c2c69f5a_20255_a2a703ac3f8d04f25559d7442adff88c.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_2/1_hufcb633eabb4ce248b64f5422c2c69f5a_20255_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_2/1_hufcb633eabb4ce248b64f5422c2c69f5a_20255_7dea048445c495e32aed14824d931f27.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;649&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular VCS was the RCS system, which is still distributed with many computers today. RCS stores sets of patches (differences between files) on disk in a special format, using which it can recreate the state of each file at a given time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;centralized-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Centralized version control systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Следующая серьёзная проблема, с которой сталкиваются люди, — это необходимость взаимодействовать с другими разработчиками. Для того, чтобы разобраться с ней, были разработаны централизованные системы контроля версий (Centralized Version Control System, далее CVCS). Такие системы, как CVS, Subversion и Perforce, используют единственный сервер, содержащий все версии файлов, и некоторое количество клиентов, которые получают файлы из этого централизованного хранилища. Применение CVCS являлось стандартом на протяжении многих лет.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Centralized version control&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_2/2_hu74fb508a0af33a33fa0f541a94378552_22810_5270c9cc3d509c774dbcc76125f1c678.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_2/2_hu74fb508a0af33a33fa0f541a94378552_22810_42d0eeea6ea2b8ccc599ff10f2bcf79c.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_2/2_hu74fb508a0af33a33fa0f541a94378552_22810_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_2/2_hu74fb508a0af33a33fa0f541a94378552_22810_5270c9cc3d509c774dbcc76125f1c678.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;528&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has many advantages, especially over local VCS. For example, all project developers know to a certain extent what each of them is doing. Administrators have full control over who can do what, and it is much easier to administer CVCS than to operate local databases on each client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, this approach also has serious disadvantages. The most obvious disadvantage is a single point of failure represented by a centralized server. If this server goes down for an hour, then during that time no one will be able to use version control to save the changes they are working on, and no one will be able to share these changes with other developers. If the hard disk on which the central database is stored is damaged, and timely backups are missing, you will lose everything — the entire history of the project, not counting the single repository snapshots that were saved on local developer machines. Local VCS suffer from the same problem: when the entire project history is stored in one place, you risk losing everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;distributed-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Distributed version control systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Distributed Version Control Systems (hereinafter DVCS) come into play. In DVCS (such as Git, Mercurial, Bazaar, or Darcs), clients don&amp;rsquo;t just download a snapshot of all files (the state of the files at a certain point in time) — they completely copy the repository. In this case, if one of the servers through which the developers exchanged data dies, any client repository can be copied to another server to continue working. Each copy of the repository is a complete backup of all data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Distributed version control&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_2/3_hu7dff96406965f7bb87732a216019226c_26657_70250987bf7266d4389417b0b0508de0.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_2/3_hu7dff96406965f7bb87732a216019226c_26657_86bb81a48ba9a95953e221f268702778.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_2/3_hu7dff96406965f7bb87732a216019226c_26657_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_2/3_hu7dff96406965f7bb87732a216019226c_26657_70250987bf7266d4389417b0b0508de0.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;635&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, many DVCS can simultaneously interact with several remote repositories, so you can work with different groups of people using different approaches at the same time within the same project. This allows you to apply several approaches to development at once, for example, hierarchical models, which is completely impossible in centralized systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (29.04.24 - 5.05.24)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-week&#34;&gt;Work week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything was fine!!!
I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy to write a post :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_8/%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%80%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BD%D0%BA%D0%B0_hu1469c4d1ccfb1161ed1445c7ce800ee1_83779_f73e2c506d0faa457620049d387d67a6.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_8/%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%80%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BD%D0%BA%D0%B0_hu1469c4d1ccfb1161ed1445c7ce800ee1_83779_2f11265bbd25101cb49618d3c4e024d0.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_8/%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%80%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BD%D0%BA%D0%B0_hu1469c4d1ccfb1161ed1445c7ce800ee1_83779_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_8/%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%80%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BD%D0%BA%D0%B0_hu1469c4d1ccfb1161ed1445c7ce800ee1_83779_f73e2c506d0faa457620049d387d67a6.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;389&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_7/%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%82%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA_hua1a9b9d35a7861e8714a0302c604396f_14265_b1d6c95dff25230f6c22426aa88b2e73.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_7/%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%82%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA_hua1a9b9d35a7861e8714a0302c604396f_14265_4ab73e36481974e6342546537d756db8.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_7/%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%82%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA_hua1a9b9d35a7861e8714a0302c604396f_14265_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%82%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA_hua1a9b9d35a7861e8714a0302c604396f_14265_b1d6c95dff25230f6c22426aa88b2e73.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;318&#34;
               height=&#34;159&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming is constantly evolving, and with it the programming languages that developers use. To be successful in the IT world, it is important to choose an up-to-date and in-demand programming language to study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-languages&#34;&gt;Programming languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;python&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_7/Python_hu49c2b606cd182cc078304b30f4dca414_505783_3c36669af24a657d5d18c6161ab45c03.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_7/Python_hu49c2b606cd182cc078304b30f4dca414_505783_723bb7c379cd9a8989796d9200889143.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_7/Python_hu49c2b606cd182cc078304b30f4dca414_505783_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/Python_hu49c2b606cd182cc078304b30f4dca414_505783_3c36669af24a657d5d18c6161ab45c03.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;391&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a general purpose programming language with a simple syntax, which makes it ideal for beginners. It is in demand in the development of web applications, scientific research, machine learning and artificial intelligence. Thanks to the rich ecosystem of libraries and tools, Python continues to hold its position as a leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_7/JavaScript_hu95054e383b84e681e7250da1c121e0aa_26693_12859fd521a781ea5ff44560a5e355f8.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_7/JavaScript_hu95054e383b84e681e7250da1c121e0aa_26693_fca18d1c2ee76781c1fc92b478aff79d.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_7/JavaScript_hu95054e383b84e681e7250da1c121e0aa_26693_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/JavaScript_hu95054e383b84e681e7250da1c121e0aa_26693_12859fd521a781ea5ff44560a5e355f8.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;700&#34;
               height=&#34;319&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript remains the main language for web development, responsible for the interactivity and dynamism of websites. With the development of frameworks and libraries such as React, Angular and Vue.js, JavaScript has become an integral part of modern web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;java&#34;&gt;Java&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_7/Java_hu17f3c14e78f2db25e9ba78bf64aea76b_51684_6891753ec67db93b52ab8e06a78578ea.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_7/Java_hu17f3c14e78f2db25e9ba78bf64aea76b_51684_b5efbad0bd80abe35e61a2b1e67724c1.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_7/Java_hu17f3c14e78f2db25e9ba78bf64aea76b_51684_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/Java_hu17f3c14e78f2db25e9ba78bf64aea76b_51684_6891753ec67db93b52ab8e06a78578ea.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;443&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java holds a special place among programming languages due to its platform independence and scalability. It is widely used for the development of Android applications and enterprise systems. Learning Java opens up access to a wide range of opportunities in different industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c&#34;&gt;C#&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_7/C 400w,
               /en/post/post_7/C 760w,
               /en/post/post_7/C 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/C&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;345&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C# was developed by Microsoft as part of the platform.NET is considered one of the most versatile programming languages. It is used to create desktop, web and mobile applications, as well as games on the Unity platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kotlin&#34;&gt;Kotlin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_7/Kotlin_hu4013986cd5e85be37ba0788b41f2f2b8_10456_b2f4b9c41bc14f813da5dc136197e56a.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_7/Kotlin_hu4013986cd5e85be37ba0788b41f2f2b8_10456_7ffd4df88b127a02c972aa72f96b9e80.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_7/Kotlin_hu4013986cd5e85be37ba0788b41f2f2b8_10456_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/Kotlin_hu4013986cd5e85be37ba0788b41f2f2b8_10456_b2f4b9c41bc14f813da5dc136197e56a.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;223&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kotlin is a modern programming language developed by JetBrains, which is rapidly gaining popularity due to its compatibility with Java and ease of use. Google officially supports Kotlin for Android app development, which makes it a sought‑after language among mobile developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;swift&#34;&gt;Swift&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_7/Swift_hu666da3284bba9119c2a9584dd35fcfdc_14590_686acc91193da9b036a92f681d08aeac.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_7/Swift_hu666da3284bba9119c2a9584dd35fcfdc_14590_684d5c7907250f929512aab6699a3ee6.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_7/Swift_hu666da3284bba9119c2a9584dd35fcfdc_14590_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/Swift_hu666da3284bba9119c2a9584dd35fcfdc_14590_686acc91193da9b036a92f681d08aeac.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;234&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swift is a programming language developed by Apple for creating native applications on iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS platforms. Fast and secure, Swift has become a key tool for Apple developers and an excellent choice for those who want to develop mobile applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;go&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_7/Go_hu171a797f2d65b4bd5e84e2d144c4a96d_10901_77f003af9f97eaa4b73fb46608f16427.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_7/Go_hu171a797f2d65b4bd5e84e2d144c4a96d_10901_956ff164e37d185e28d85dafe20dd20b.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_7/Go_hu171a797f2d65b4bd5e84e2d144c4a96d_10901_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/Go_hu171a797f2d65b4bd5e84e2d144c4a96d_10901_77f003af9f97eaa4b73fb46608f16427.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;286&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go, or Golang, is a programming language created at Google to address scalability and efficiency issues. It is easy to learn, fast and reliable, which makes it popular for building high-performance systems such as cloud services and network applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rust&#34;&gt;Rust&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Rust.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust is a programming language developed by Mozilla with a focus on security and performance. Due to its unique memory management mechanisms and parallelism approach, Rust attracts the attention of developers and becomes an attractive language to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;typescript&#34;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_7/TypeScript_huf984d056b548e4e63bbc41c639d029fe_16523_8761a49a894f653ce4017c87f3d3743d.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_7/TypeScript_huf984d056b548e4e63bbc41c639d029fe_16523_7957a1395cd022df2ae35df1d07062c1.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_7/TypeScript_huf984d056b548e4e63bbc41c639d029fe_16523_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/TypeScript_huf984d056b548e4e63bbc41c639d029fe_16523_8761a49a894f653ce4017c87f3d3743d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;187&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TypeScript is an add—on to JavaScript developed by Microsoft to improve static typing and code scalability. TypeScript allows you to detect errors at the stage of writing code, which improves the quality and reliability of applications being developed. Integration with popular frameworks makes TypeScript a sought‑after language among web developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ruby&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/post_7/Ruby_huf1566dc3908f2a93bfe8ac9f6c2112fc_571448_3e65d82f44e09b17ec6dc4cc6db9791c.webp 400w,
               /en/post/post_7/Ruby_huf1566dc3908f2a93bfe8ac9f6c2112fc_571448_6aab8f07245c94cfca33f2a602a22578.webp 760w,
               /en/post/post_7/Ruby_huf1566dc3908f2a93bfe8ac9f6c2112fc_571448_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/post/post_7/Ruby_huf1566dc3908f2a93bfe8ac9f6c2112fc_571448_3e65d82f44e09b17ec6dc4cc6db9791c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;309&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruby is another general–purpose programming language known for its expressive and readable syntax. The main advantage of Ruby is the Ruby on Rails framework, which greatly simplifies the development of web applications and makes Ruby relevant for web developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
